<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-04-10T20:22:00+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Palmaz Ahmad</title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Webpage Containg Palmaz Ahmads portfolio. This includes a Blog and Projects both previously worked on and current.</subtitle>
  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Goals for 2020</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/Goals-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goals for 2020" />
      <published>2020-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/personal/Goals-2020</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/Goals-2020/">&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;Personal Goals &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my personal Goals I have a few in mind. Some may seem easy and other won’t, reason for the variety is as I want to challenge myself as well as have fun. If the goals don’t challenge you to a certain extent then there’s no point of them. Mine are Technical Goals as this is the area I want to improve this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; My goals this year include:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Post at least one blog per month&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Learn Python to an Advanced level&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Use a new tool/ software every month&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Improve my web dev skills &lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;Placement Goals &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently reached the 6th month mark in my placement and I have achieved my goals I set for myself at this point. I really want to expand my network and skills and the best way I see this happening is by working with people across the business in areas I wouldn’t necessarily work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; My goals this year include:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Present Externally&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Complete Current Data Migration Successfully&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Branch out to teams in R&amp;amp;D or Manufacturing&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Improve internal Communication&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be writing an update post every now and again with a progress report which will likely be linked below this if one exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note - These Goals may be adapted or changed depending on performance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-be-continued&quot;&gt;TO BE CONTINUED…&lt;/h3&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Posted by - Palmaz Ahmad on </name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="Personal" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Personal Goals For my personal Goals I have a few in mind. Some may seem easy and other won’t, reason for the variety is as I want to challenge myself as well as have fun. If the goals don’t challenge you to a certain extent then there’s no point of them. Mine are Technical Goals as this is the area I want to improve this year! My goals this year include: Post at least one blog per month Learn Python to an Advanced level Use a new tool/ software every month Improve my web dev skills</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Importing Large Data Sets</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/Large-Data-Sets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Importing Large Data Sets" />
      <published>2020-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/tech/Large-Data-Sets</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/Large-Data-Sets/">&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;Working With Large Data Sets &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people don’t realise how difficult it can be when working with large data sets. Often people resort to using Excel to view and manipulate their data, this works sometimes &lt;strong&gt;but not every time&lt;/strong&gt;. Excel has certain limitations which confine the data itself. These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Row limit of &lt;strong&gt;1,048,576&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Column limit of &lt;strong&gt;16,384&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue can be problematic especially if you work with large data sets. I personally had this problem as some imports held over 12 million records per Object / Class and Excel just wasn’t the tool to use. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;If you want to view your Data there are some options available to you at this point: &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; 1. Import into a Database&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Databases allow you to store data in fields and tables with no limit in size. You can set constraints on the  fields too, to match your data. The Database is really your choice but lately I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org&quot;&gt;Postgres&lt;/a&gt;. The syntax is slightly different to mysql but its really simple to use. Once you have everything set up and ready to go all you have to do is import your data. Depending on the number of fields - I set the fields myself as you have control on the data types and other extras such as ‘Not Null’, ‘Primary Key’ etc. And that’s it. Now you can use SQL to query the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Postgres Pg4 admin tool, to view all your data use this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-SQL&quot;&gt;SELECT * 
FROM public.&quot;TABLENAME&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One annoying problem is unlike other major data management studios it doesn’t include the functionality of reading the first column lines as fields automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;2. Power Pivot (In Excel)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to stick to excel but have too much data you can use Power Pivot. This tool allows you to analyse large datasets, it can handle 100+ million rows. It’s considered as using a pivot table for a large dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great when it comes to importing data from multiple source. This means you can import .SQL, .txt, Access database document and others. This gives you the freedom of being able to Import any type of data file, even if your data is in a standard text file. (Please use CSV…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;3. Microsoft Access&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool is another database but simpler format. You can straight type or enter what settings you want and import data easily using .CSV. This is great if you have never used SQL or not too great at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; Overall &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other ways to import large data which I haven’t mentioned above but these are the most common. Especially if you want to view and manipulate it. I personally prefer the database method as I can call and edit what I want and using SQL is much easier for me rather than click and drag.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Posted by - Palmaz Ahmad on </name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="Tech" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Working With Large Data Sets Many people don’t realise how difficult it can be when working with large data sets. Often people resort to using Excel to view and manipulate their data, this works sometimes but not every time. Excel has certain limitations which confine the data itself. These include:</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Big Data LDN Conference 2019</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/BigDataLDN/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Data LDN Conference 2019" />
      <published>2020-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/tech/BigDataLDN</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/BigDataLDN/">&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;  What is Big Data LDN? &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Data LDN (London) is a tech conferenece focusing on Data. It’s a free two day event held in Olympia London, honestly it’s a combination between a ‘Conference’ and an ‘Exibition’. There were 4 ‘technical talk’ theatres Confernece halls and 4 ‘Strategy Sessions’ where comapines would come and talk about either something they are working on or created or a particular problem/ concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;  Why did I go? &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended this conference for many reasons. My reasons where both personal and business related as I could use the knowledge gained at this event to better myself and also bring insightful information back to the company Im currently working for. Here’s some of the reasons why I went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt; To Network &lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt; Understand Data's progression in Industry&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt; Attend my first major professional conference. &lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt; What companies are trying to do with their Data.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt; Find out What tools are out there&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;IBM - 'WATSON'&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bigdataldn.com/seminar-schedule/how-ai-gives-you-superpowers/&quot;&gt;IBM talk&lt;/a&gt; presented by &lt;strong&gt;Rob Thomas&lt;/strong&gt; (General Manager - IBM Data &amp;amp; AI), he spoke a lot about AI and the direction businesses can go towards using AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;AI is: &lt;i&gt;‘Predictions + Automation + Optimisation’&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly AI (Artificial Intelligence) is intelligence showed by a computer/machine which is simillar to natural intelligence showed by us humans.  &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;‘AI is only as good as your data’&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - Very true, if data is bad then AI intelligence is bad which results to weak decision making leading to bad results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for the AI heavy talk, ‘Watson’ - a tool/ service IBM offer to help other business use AI. Throughout the talk Mr Thomas Spoke about the benifits of AI and why its the future. But that’s a Converstation for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key takeaway was the importance of good data. Good data can enable business to be more effiecent as the data they have can optimise processes and increase efficiency. Again this is a converstation for another blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt;  Some Intresting Facts - &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt;In the last two years -&amp;gt; 90% of all data has been collected. &lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt;only around 9% of business deal with &lt;i&gt;'Data Maturity'&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;h6&gt; Problems which they face include - 'Complexity &amp;amp; Security'&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt; Only 10% of business have adopted AI &lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h5&gt; Information drives value (Business value)&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h6&gt;2009 Largest Companies included - PetroChina, Exxon Mobil, Industrial &amp;amp; Commercial Bank of China, China Mobile, Microsoft. (Only two out of top 10 Companies are tech related)&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;h6&gt; 2019 Largest Companies included - 
    Apple, Microsoft, Amazon, Alphabet, Berkshire Hathaway (8 out of top 10 Companies)&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Statistics provided by IBM, Clouderia, Colibria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; What It made me realise: &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my placement I’ve noticed many things, one being having good organised data is easier said than done - I found this out the hard way! I started by doing some basic anaylsis on some of our data and came to some shocking conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some objects / fields weren’t even being used often or at all, we were collecting data which wasn’t benifiting us as all. Overall our data was a mess and we weren’t utilising it well enough. Since then we have made more of an effort to understand our business needs and what we can do with exisiting data and using it to aid decision making for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; My overall thoughts: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Pros&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cons&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;li&gt; Structure of the day was great&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;li&gt; Some talks became adverts to their product, no learning oppotunities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;li&gt; Data LDN app was useful for planning the day and view oppotunities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;li&gt; Too many similar products/ tools, nothing stood out well&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;li&gt; Interesting Concepts covered such as, Data visualisation and cloud              computing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;li&gt; Scan Badges and take personal details, only to harrass you later!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was an interesting in terms of concepts and tools being created and their purpose. It was great to see the value of ‘good data’ finally being noticed! Often people think quanitity over quality, which is not the case. Good data leads to good decision making and higher effeciency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The a common trend in industry at the moment is cloud based storage and this is propelled further by companies such as Microsoft, Google and Amazon, Who in turn have created cloud based software such as Microsoft Azure (Which is use), AWS and Google Cloud Platform. - This trend is true as i’m currently working a lot in the Azure space myself using facilities such as Data Lake, Data Warehouse, SQL server and Database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common trend I noticed was companies are organising their data to try to take advantage of AI. This concept requires good, organised, structured data to work effectively. IBM have createed a tool named ‘Watson’ which can be deployed to help business create AI for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Posted by - Palmaz Ahmad on </name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="Tech" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">What is Big Data LDN? Big Data LDN (London) is a tech conferenece focusing on Data. It’s a free two day event held in Olympia London, honestly it’s a combination between a ‘Conference’ and an ‘Exibition’. There were 4 ‘technical talk’ theatres Confernece halls and 4 ‘Strategy Sessions’ where comapines would come and talk about either something they are working on or created or a particular problem/ concept.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Hi Everyone, I’m Palmaz</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/PalmazAhmad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hi Everyone, I'm Palmaz" />
      <published>2019-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/personal/PalmazAhmad</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/PalmazAhmad/">&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; Who am I? &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello, My name is Palmaz. I’m a 20 year old Computing student currently on Placement, as an Data Analyst. I began my placement with little knowledge of working with large data, manipulating large datasets and working with data in general. But I’ll leave my placement learning’s in upcoming posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; Why make this website?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make my first post about my reasons for making this site and what I hope to learn in the process. Firstly I came up with the idea a few months ago, I wanted to create a website of some sort as I wanted to develop my web development skills. But I wasn’t sure what to make the site on, I started brain storming potential ideas which would give me plenty of learning opportunities as well as challenge me. I always wanted a platform in which I could display my projects which I work on in my own time. So I decided to create a webpage which would act as my Portfolio as well as a place for me to share my thoughts and findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; My main reasons for creating this page were: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt;To get experience in creating and maintaining webpages/ Improve my web dev skills&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt; Start my portfolio &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt; Improve my writing skills - *Not my strong suit* &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt; Create a long term project &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt; Showcase my general finding's &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; My Hobbies &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- ![1stdegree](/img/1stblackbelt.jpg)  ![Blackbelt](/img/blackbelt.jpg)   --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blackbelt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BlackBelt 2nd Degree&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;padding:10px&quot; /&gt;
   Since the age of 4 I've trained in multiple martial arts such as Kickboxing (&amp;amp; American Style), Taekwondo (Traditional &amp;amp; Competitive), MMA, Thai Boxing, Boxing, Hapkido and others. I've competed internationally and won majors. I have over 14 years experience and have recently stopped to pursue other interests. I currently hold a 2nd Degree Blackbelt in Taekwondo (ITF). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also enjoy creating small but useful projects in my free time, I have recently started learning Python. The reason why I decided to learn Python was automation. At work I needed to automate the process of exporting meta data from a system.  I needed to extract from an .XML and (extracting certain tags) import them into an excel work sheet. I spoke to a colleague, who suggested a Python script. At the time I had never created a script so my colleague helped me create a script to automate this large process. Again I'll go into detail about this script another time. Since then I've been learning and creating scripts for automating tasks as well as for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;PostH1&quot;&gt; Sneak Peak - Likey to be the next Posts!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt;Goals for 2020 &lt;/li&gt;&lt;h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt;Python Scripts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palmazahmad.com/tech/BigDataLDN/&quot;&gt;Big Data LDN 2019 [Click me]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palmazahmad.com/tech/Large-Data-Sets/&quot;&gt;Importing Large Data Sets [Click me] &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;





&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Posted by - Palmaz Ahmad on </name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="Personal" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Who am I?</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
